# **CHRIS FISHER**

# **Senior Software Engineer**

254-258-9604 | clfshr@gmail.com | chrsfshr.com

# **CAREER SUMMARY:**

Solution-oriented problem solver with 10 years of experience building and maintaining web application software. Highly skilled in communication, between the technical disciplines of design and development. Solving challenges at every touch point in a project's journey, from ideation to technical application.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# **Senior Front-End Engineer**

HUVR Data | Dec 2022 - Present

- Utilized Material UI framework and React.js to develop highly interactive and responsive user interfaces for web applications.
- Implemented reusable UI components and layouts, enhancing development efficiency and maintaining a consistent user experience across the application.
- Integrated Redux into the front-end architecture, enabling efficient state management and predictable data flow within the application.
- Handled Redux stores, reducers, and actions to handle complex application state, ensuring data consistency and synchronization across different components.

# **Senior Software Engineer**

IBM Quantum | Nov 2018 - Dec 2022

- Led development for the IBM Quantum Experience team in building the first and only flagship marketing web application for IBM Quantum.
- Advised and collaborated with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, product managers and stakeholders on technical application.
- Helped solidify and grow IBM Quantum's brand recognition in organic SEO growth for keywords to #1 on Google.
- Worked with a variety of different languages and frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Node.js, SASS, Strapi, Directus.

# Software Developer

IBM Watson Education | April 2016 - Nov 2018

- Worked in a team of 3 developers to engineer and implement IBM's first industry application using AI (Watson) specific to helping teachers manage their classrooms.
- Engineered and maintained major features and UI components for 2 major market releases.
- Proposed and implemented scalable solutions to address application accessibility and inclusion from development to design.
- Worked with a variety of different languages and frameworks: JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, SASS

# Associate Web Developer

Charity Dynamics | February 2014 - May 2016

- Developed digital marketing experiences and websites for donors and constituents of national non profits.
- Engineered web donation campaigns that have resulted in donation amounts of more than 1Million dollars for national non-profits like Humane Society and American Heart Association.
- Built email marketing templates to be used in communication for potential donors

# **Systems Support Specialist III**

Texas Department of Family & Protective Svcs | September 2008 - November 2013

- Provided customer service and answers user inquiries regarding computer software, hardware, and the use of systems and software applications.
- Setup images on tablets and digital equipment by adding software to computers for existing and new employees.
- Maintained the network's physical and logical structures, including network connections.
- Provided employee support and training in the use of available hardware, software, and utilities.

### **SKILLS:**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/Sass
- Libraries & Frameworks: React, Vue, Angular, Node.js, Gatsby, Drupal, Wordpress, AEM
- Design/Tools: Sketch, Figma, Invision, Mural, Git, Webpack, Docker, Design Thinking, Agile Workflow

### **HONORS & ACTIVITIES**

### Code Mentor | Latinitas Austin, TX

Latinitas, a nonprofit organization focused on empowering Latina youth through technology and media. Girls and teens received lessons in code languages, brainstorm a project to apply such skills and then will carry out the project implementation in a hackathon style with the help of experienced coders.

### Speaker and Mentor | Black Thought Leadership Movement 50 Austin, TX

Presented at SXSW: Diversity Hackathon where I mentored and judged hackathon projects for attendees and participants focused on closing the minority gap in the tech industry.

### Co-Founder and Mentor | Spectrum Austin, TX

Co-created a design and develop bootcamp for underprivileged elementary and middle school students. Who have shown interest in the tech and science industry.

### **EDUCATION:**

2006 - 2009 | ITT Technical Insititute - Austin

Applied Science - Electronic Computer Engineering